[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Good morning everybody, I'm
&gt;&gt; 大家早上好
Vincent Hittson, Cocoa engineer
我是 Cocoa 工程师 Vincent Hittson
along with Rachel Goldeen, Cocoa
这位是 Rachel Goldeen  也是 Cocoa 工程师
engineer and welcome to Cocoa
欢迎来到 “Cocoa
Development Tips.
开发技巧”会场
Rachel is going to start us off.
首先将有请 Rachel 为我们做开场白
&gt;&gt; Good morning, we have a wide
&gt;&gt; 早上好 今天上午
array of tips to show you this
我们将向大家广泛地展示
morning, we're going to speed
一系列开发技巧
through them.
我们会抓紧时间逐一讲解
And it was a little tricky to
关于这些议题 如果想要弄清楚
figure out how to order them,
它们的安排顺序
what kind of sequence or
应该使用什么样的顺序或编码系统
numbering system to use, we
可能会有些棘手
think we got something really
但最终我们还是想到了一些
good.
不错的方法
I'm going to start you out with
首先 我给大家从
a quick tip to get things going.
一个快速技巧开始讲起
Number pi internationalization
也就是数字 π 的国际化
because it's all Greek to us.
因为我们都对此一窍不通
Just take a look at the Xcode
我们只需观察一下 Xcode 的方案编辑器
Scheme Editor and in the run
在它的运行部分里
section you'll notice there's
你-会发现其中有一个
this location debugging section.
定位调试部分
You can check the show
你可以勾选
nonlocalized strings checkbox
“显示非本地化字符串”的复选框
and see where your app is
然后查看你的 App 里
missing localized strings.
本地化字符串的缺失位置
But I'd like to focus your
但我希望你能将注意力
attention on this application
放到这个应用程序的语言
language menu.
菜单上
Down at the bottom there's a
在菜单底部
list of pseudolanguages that you
有一个伪语言列表
can use before your translations
你可以在翻译完成之前使用它
have been made and this will
它将显示你的 App 是否
show you if your app is ready
已经做好了那些
for those translations.
翻译准备
Okay that's it, back to Vince.
OK 就是这样 现在再请 Vince 来讲解
&gt;&gt; Okay tip number zero, user
&gt;&gt; 好的“技巧 0 用户默认设置”
defaults since zero makes a
因为零是一个
pretty good default value.
不错的默认值
So, you have your standard user
你有自己的标准用户默认设置
defaults and this is what you
用于获取和设置
use to get and set your user
你自己的用户偏好
preferences, but it's not just a
但它不仅仅是一大堆
big bag of preferences it's
偏好设置的汇集
actually a set of domains and
它实际上是一组域
each of those domains have their
其中每个域都有
own bags and here's a subset of
自己的单位组
those.
这就是它们的子集
And when you ask the standard
当你要求标准用户默认设置
user defaults for a value it
返回一个值时
checks each of these domains in
它会按顺序逐个检查这些域
order returning the first value
并返回到它发现的
it finds.
第一个值
And you can set values in these
你可以用这些域自身的技巧
domains using their own
在它们之中设置值
techniques and we're going to go
我们现在要以相反的顺序
through them in reverse order.
来审视它们
So, starting at the bottom is
所以 从最基础的开始
the registration domain, it's
首先是注册域
last in the list and you use the
它是列表的最后一个
register method, passing in the
你使用注册方法
dictionary of the user defaults,
传入用户默认设置
keys and values.
键  以及值的字典
And it's temporary so it's only
而这些只是临时的
available for the lifetime of
所以它只在这个特定过程的
this particular process.
生命周期里可用
The next time your app launches
等到下次启动 App 时
you'll have to call register
你必须再次调用
again.
注册
So, use this to provide initial
所以 它为你的默认设置
values for your defaults without
提供初始值
setting them permanently.
而不是永久值
Next up is the global domain.
下面一个是全局域
This is shared by all
它由所有的应用程序共享
applications and it's commonly
System framework
used by system frameworks to
通常用它来存储
store systemwide preferences.
系统范围内的偏好
And you can set it using the
你可以使用默认命令行工具
defaults command line tool, but
来设置这个域
it's persistent so any changes
但这一设置是持久的
you make are going to be
所以你做过的任何改动都会保留下来
permanent so be aware of that.
因此对这一点要有所意识
Next up is the application
下一个是应用程序域
domain and when you set a value
当你在标准用户默认设置中
on the standard user defaults
使用 Set 方法来
using the set method it goes
设定某个值的时候
here.
它就出现在这里
And this domain is persistent so
而且这个域也是持久的
the next time your user launches
下一次当你的用户启动 App 时
your app it'll have the value
你原先设置的值仍将存在
that you set so you'll want to
所以当你的用户
use this when your user actually
在初始值中修改偏好时
changes a preference from the
你就会想到
initial value.
要使用它
Last or first, but not least is
无论位于首位或末尾  实参域
the argument domain and the
都同样的重要
argument domain is really cool.
这个域真的很酷
So, you can pass your user
你可以把自己的
defaults key as an argument to
用户默认键和值
your application along with the
一并作为实际参数传入应用
value and you prepend your user
并使用连字符预先
defaults key with a hyphen.
添加用户默认键
And it's first in the list, so
因为它处于列表的第一位
it overrides the values of all
所以它覆盖所有
those other domains.
其他域的值
And it's temporary, so it's only
它也是临时的 所以只有当
set when your app is launched
你启动 App 以及那些特定实参的时候
with these particular arguments.
才能够对它进行设置
If you run your app and these
如果你运行 App
arguments aren't there the
但却没有那些实参
values won't be there.
那么就不会出现任何值
So, this is really handy if
所以如果你想要
you're trying to reproduce an
重现与用户偏好有关的问题
issue involving user preferences
这是十分便利的方法
and you don't want to actually
另外你也并不想真的
set them on your machine or for
在自己的机器上对它们进行设置
just enabling a debug flag.
或者仅只是为了启用调试旗标而设置
And speaking of debug flags,
说到调试旗标
AppKit has a couple, here's some
AppKit 里就有好几个
that you can use.
以下这些是大家可以使用的
NSiewLayoutFeedback
NSiewLayoutFeedbackLoopDebuggingEnabled
set this to yes if your app is
如果你的 App 在布局时一直出现卡顿
getting stuck repeatedly doing
可以把这个标记
layout.
设置为 YES
The feedback loop debugger will
FeedbackLoopDebugger 会
help you track down that that
帮助你追踪
issue.
那个问题
Next is NSApplicationCrash
还有一个是
OnExceptions and use this in
NSApplicationCrashOnExceptions
NSApplication if it catches an
它在 NSApplication 中使用时 如果它捕获了异常
exception it'll crash your app.
将会导致你的 App 崩溃
So, it's a good thing to have on
所以 在开发过程中找到这些工具
during development so you find
是件不错的事情  这样你就可以发现
those issues.
那些问题
And you probably want to use the
当然你也可能想要使用
argument domain to set these so
实参域来设置这些
you don't shift with them so
这样你就不会随之改变
that's a good idea.
这也是个好办法
Here's a neat thing about the
关于标准用户默认设置
standard user defaults, it
有一个巧妙之处在于
supports key-value observing or
它支持键值观察
KVO.
也就是 KVO
You just add your observer with
你只需添加观测器
the user defaults key as your
将用户默认键
keyPath and any time that value
作为你的键路径 并且在
changes even if it's from
这个值发生每一次改动时
another process you'll get
即使发生于其它的进程
notified.
你都会收到相应的通知
So, here's an example of what
这里有一个例子可以
that looks like.
说明基本情况
We add an observer using the
我们添加一个观测器  使用的是
addObserver for keypad options
addObserver forKeyPath options context 方法
context method and pass our user
并用字符串的形式
defaults key as a sting.
传入了我们的用户默认键
And of course, when we're no
当然 如果我们对
longer interested in watching
观察这些变化不再感兴趣
for these changes we remove our
可以将设置的这个观测器
observer.
移除
And in the meantime, you'll get
在此期间 每当默认值有所更改
an observeValue for keyPath call
你就会收到一个
out any time your defaults value
通过键路径调出的
changes.
observeValue
So that's about that, here's
以上就是关于键值观察的内容
what that looks like in diagram
这个过程就像是图表里展示的
form.
那样
So, if your application sets a
因此  如果你的应用设置了一个
user default and you have an
用户默认值  而且你有一个
observer registered it will be
已注册的观测器 那么
notified of that change.
它会收到该改动的通知
And similarly, if another
与此类似
process sets a value for one of
如果另一个过程也设置了
your user defaults that you're
你正在观测的用户默认值
observing, you will be notified
你也会同样收到
of that as well.
相关通知
So, it's pretty straightforward.
所以说  这个操作非常简单直接
Here's another neat trick.
另外还有一个简单技巧
So, if you want that new keyPath
如果你想得到你在
syntax and that block-based
“Foundation 的新功能”会议上
observe method that you heard
听说的新键路径语法和
about in what's new in
基于块的观察方法
Foundation you can do that with
你可以通过用户默认设置
user defaults.
来实现
You just need to add an
只需添加一个 Extention
extension and add at an @objc
以及和你的用户默认键
dynamic property that has the
名称相同的 @objc 动态属性
same name as your user defaults
就可以了
key and that's really important.
这一点十分重要
If the names don't match this
如果两个名字不匹配
isn't going to work.
那么这项操作就无法进行
And you can as a convenience
为了方便起见 你可以
implement your property getter
执行你的属性 Getter
to return the value.
来返回这个值
And then you can use the
然后你可以使用
block-based observe method along
基于块的观察方法
with the keyPath literal syntax
再加上键路径字面量句法
that's new and it works just
这新推出的方法
like you'd expect.
效果如同你期待的那样
So that's it for user defaults.
以上就是用户默认设置的内容
Next up is tip number 64, what
接下来是“技巧 64 ”
is that?
这是什么
Oh, base 64 right.
噢 Base 64  是的
So, for those that aren't
给不熟悉 Base64 的人解释一下
familiar base 64 is an encoding
Base64 是一种编码
that lets you represent any data
可以让你通过使用一组简单的 ASCII
using a simple set of ASCII.
来表示任何数据
So, this is handy of you want to
所以 如果你想要测试
have a test or an easy to copy
或者轻松复制粘贴
paste and share snippet of code
并分享包含二进制数据的代码片段
that includes some binary data
Base64 会很有用
and you don't want to worry
你不需要为
about packaging that up and
数据打包和查看寻找
having to look it up and all
以及所有的一切
that.
而担心
And NSData supports base 64 and
NSData 支持 Base64
you can create a data from the
你可以在数据上使用
base 64 string using the base 64
Base64 编码初始化器
encoded initializer on data and
从Base64 字符串中创建一个数据
you'll get back your data.
这样你将恢复你的数据
And then you can use it [sound
然后你可以用它来
effect] for example, to play a
比如说 播放一个声音
And now if you want to create
现在 如果你要创建
these base 64 strings you can
这些 Base64 字符串
use the base 64 encoded string
你可以在数据上使用
method on data to get those
Base64 编码字符串方法 以此获取
strings.
这些字符串
There's also a base 64 command
你还可以在终端使用
line utility that you can use in
Base64 命令行实用程序
terminal to get your base 64
以获取你的 Base64 字符串
strings and that's base 64.
以上就是 Base64 的内容
Now back to Rachel.
现在 我把舞台交给 Rachel
talk about asset catalogs a
聊一聊资源目录
little bit.
的话题
Many of you are already using
你们当中很多人已经在使用
asset catalogs, you know that
资源目录了  大家都知道
they organizer your images,
它们能整理你的图片
speed up launch times, reduce
加快启动时间
storage space.
减少存储空间
And I'd like to talk about a few
而我-要讨论的是在去年
things that were added last year
macOS Sierra 以及 iOS 10 上
in macOS Sierra and iOS 10 in
新增加的一些内容
case you hadn't heard about
以免没有听过的人
them.
对此毫无了解
First, there's layout direction.
首先 这是一个布局方向
This action image is symmetrical
这个动作图片是对称的
and it doesn't matter, it'll be
因此不受影响
the same both left to right and
它从左到右和从右到左
right to left so the direction
都是一样的
is fixed.
所以它的方向是固定的
But here's a GoForward image and
但这里有一个前进图片
in right to left languages
在从右到左书写的语言中
GoForward means to the left
前进表示向左
whereas left to right means it's
反之 在从左到右书写的语言中
going to the right.
前进表示向右
So, we want it to mirror for the
所以 我们想让这个图片在另一个语言中
other language.
实现镜像翻转
And then a little more
然后发现情况有点复杂
sophisticated is when you have
当你有一张图片
an image that needs to be
需要根据布局方向
different for the layout
而做出相应改变
directions, but isn't a mirror
但又不是镜像改变时
image, such as this autofill
例如在这个自动填充图片中
image where the dots indicating
这些点点表示书写内容
what has been written are to the
它们依照从左到右的顺序
left of the pencil in left to
位于铅笔左侧
right and to the right of the
位于铅笔右边的
pencil in right to left, but the
则是从右到左的顺序
pencil still tilts to the right.
但铅笔仍向右倾斜
So, they're not mirror images
所以 它们并非镜像
and the designer decided it was
设计师认为
worth it to provide two
有必要再提供
different images, but asset
两张不同的图片 但是
catalogs will handle this for
资源目录就会替你
you.
处理好这个问题
Next, I'd like to talk about
接下来我们要讨论
display gamut and that's the
显示器色域
different kind of color
它指的是不同显示器上可用的
representations that are
不同类型的
available on different displays,
颜色显示
the older displaces use sRGB,
旧的显示器使用 sRGB
the newer ones with brighter,
而新显示器的颜色更加明亮 丰富
richer colors use Display P3.
它们使用的是 Display P3
I've overexaggerated the
我放大了这些图片之间
difference between these images,
存在的差别
but just to show you that asset
不过这只是为了向大家展示
catalogs allow you to specify
资源目录可以让你
specific images for the two
为这两个不同的显示器色域
different display gamuts.
判定具体的图片
In iOS 11 and macOS Sierra we
在 iOS 11 和 macOS Sierra 中
added colors to asset catalogs.
我们给资源目录增加了颜色
So, you can make a named color
所以你可以使用一个有名字的颜色
just my simple accent color here
就像我这个简单的强调色
and you can also if you need to
如果你需要的话 还可以
specify sRGB and Display P3
指定该颜色的 sRGB 和 Display P3
versions of that color.
版本
To use it in code we want to use
为了在代码里能够使用它
this new API.
我们要使用这个新的 API
You can add your name to the
你可以将自己的名字添加到
extensible NSColor.Name enum and
可扩展的 NSColor.Name 枚举里
then use the color named
然后使用已命名颜色的
initializer with your name to
初始化器  用自己的名字来
create your color it's as easy
来创建自己的颜色
as that.
就是如此简单
Next up number one, unit tests.
接下来是“技巧 1 单元测试”
Sometimes there's a
有时编写单元测试时
psychological barrier to writing
会存在一种心理障碍
unit tests, it seems like it's
它看起来似乎很难
going to be hard, but I'm here
但今天我要向大家展示
to show you how easy it can be.
它有多么简单
Create a new file in Xcode, make
在 Xcode 中新建一个文件
it a unit test case class, Xcode
让它成为一个单元测试样本分类
will give you a template, you
Xcode 会给你一个模板
can fill it in with something as
你可以在里面填充一些
easy as this.
像这样简单的内容
Here I've created my addCatImage
我在这里创建了我的 addCatImage
and I'm checking to see that
并且要通过检查来确定
it's not nil.
它不是空的
It's just a sanity check, is my
这只是一个完整性检查
asset catalog on and working.
检查我的资源目录是否已打开并在运行
And once you've got one unit
一旦你获得了一个编写好的
test written it's much easier to
单元测试  那么编写额外的测试
write additional tests and
并且避免自己的用户
prevent bugs from getting out to
碰到错误
your users.
就变得更加容易了
Back to Vince.
好 让 Vince 再来讲讲
&gt;&gt; Okay tip number 27, NSBox.
&gt;&gt; 好的 “技巧 27 NSBox”
Sometimes all you want is a
有时候 你想要的只是
simple view that shows a
一个显示背景颜色的
background color.
简单视图
And you control it may be like
你可能是像这样控制它
this, so you can implement one
这样你就可以执行
and you can make it layered back
甚至可以让它分层
even and that's fine or you can
这很好  或者你也可以
let AppKit do it for you.
让 AppKit 为你代劳
We have NSBox all you need to do
我们拥有 NSBox 以后 你只需要
is set the box type to custom
把框类型设为自定义
and then configure it setting
然后让它把背景设置为
the fill color.
填充色彩
And this would be more dynamic
这比只在一个层面
than just setting the background
设置背景颜色
color on a layer because if the
更具动态性  因为如果
color's a system color that
该颜色为系统颜色
changes dynamically based on
是基于外观或语境而产生
appearance or context NSBox will
动态改变的话
update automatically.
NSBox 将会对它进行自动更新
And even better, you can drag it
更胜一筹的是 你可以把它
out of Interface Builder and
从 Interface Builder 里拖出来
configure it from there.
并从那里对它进行设置
And there are several properties
你可以用几种属性
that you can use to configure a
来设置某个
custom box.
自定义框
There's border width, corner
要有边框宽度 圆角半径
radius, border color and of
边框颜色 当然
course, fill color so use that.
还有颜色填充 像这样来使用
And you can even set a content
甚至你也可以在框里
view on a box to show another
设置一个内容视图
view inside the box, so it's
来显示框里的另一个视图
really easy.
所以这真的很简单
And that's not all, sometimes
当然 还不止这些
all you want is a simple
有时 你想要的
separator and NSBox has you
只是一个简单的分隔符
covered there too.
这一点 NSBox 也能办到
All you need to do is create a
你所要做的  只是
box with the separator type and
创建一个带有分隔符类型的框
position it however you like.
并把它放在你喜欢的位置
And of course, it's available
当然 它可以从
from Interface Builder.
Interface Builder 那里获得
So that's NSBox it should make
所以这就是 NSBox
creating your user interfaces a
它会让用户界面的创建
lot easier.
更加容易
Next up is tip number eight,
接下来是“技巧 8 可恢复
restorable state.
状态”
So, macOS has a feature where
macOS 有一个功能可以
you can restart your machine and
让你重启机器
all your running applications
让你所有正在运行的应用
come back and using this
都恢复状态
invaluable trio of methods on
通过使用 NSResponder 上
NSResponder you can bring your
这个价值极高的三种方法组合
user right back to where they
可以让用户回到
left off.
离开时的状态
And most AppKit controls will
大部分 AppKit 控件
have these implemented for you,
都会替你执行这些方法
but if you have your own
但如果你有自己的控件
controls or restorable state,
或是可恢复状态
you can implement them
你就可以自己来执行
yourselves.
这些方法-
And this is what that might look
事情大概就是
like.
这样
So, you have your properties
所以 你要拥有自己的属性
that are your restorable state,
这就是你自己的可恢复状态
when they change you invalidate
当它们改变时
restorable state.
你的可恢复状态就失效
And then at some point, the
然后 在某一时刻
system will call in code
这个系统将会调用
restorable state so you take the
代码可恢复状态 于是
values from your properties and
你就可以从你的属性里找到值
put them in the coder and then
并将它们放入编码器中
when your application is
然后当你的应用重启时
relaunched we'll call restore
我们会使用编码器
state with coder and you take
调用可恢复状态
the values out your coder and
你再将编码器中的值调出
put them in the properties.
并放到属性里
It's pretty straightforward and
一目了然
pretty easy, but there is an
易如反掌 但还有一种
easier way.
更简单的办法
NSResponder has this class
NSResponder 有这样一个类属性
property restorableStateKeyPaths
restorableStateKeyPaths
and this can point to any
它可以指向任意一个
NSCoding conforming type and
NSCoding 符合类型
AppKit will use key value
AppKit 将使用键值观察
observing to watch for changes
来观察这些属性
to these properties.
的改变
So that means when restoring
这就意味着在恢复状态时
will automatically set the
它将自动为你设置各种值
values for you, so it's really
所以真的很简单
Do note that these properties
要注意 这些属性是被
are marked @objc dynamic and so
标记了 @objc 动态
that's key value observing can
因此  键值观察才可以
do its automatic notification.
实现自动通知
And you can still use this with
你也可以通过其他的
the other state restoration
状态恢复来调出
callouts.
使用它
You can use this for your simple
你可以为你的简单属性而使用它
properties and then use those
再把其它的调出用于
other callouts for other bits of
你可能会有的  其它部分的
restorable state you may have,
可恢复状态
they work together.
它们会一起协作
All right, now back to Rachel.
好 现在有请 Rachel
&gt;&gt; Okay I'm going to tell you a
&gt;&gt; 好的 我将要告诉大家
sequence of tips about Core Data
关于 Core Data 的一系列技巧
that build upon each other and
这些技巧相互依托建构
I'm starting with number 13
而我将从“技巧 13 ”开始
because you may have been
因为可能比较遗憾的是
unlucky enough in the past to
在去年 Sierra 和 iOS 10
have to set up a Core Data Stack
添加 NSPersistentContainer 之前
before the existence of
你可能不得不
NSPersistentContainer that was
自己构建 Core Data Stack
added last year in Sierra and
这样一个
iOS 10.
数据堆栈
Core Data Stack consists of a
Core Data Stack 包括
managed object model and then
一个托管对象模型
you have a persistent store
然后你会有一个
coordinator that coordinates one
持久化存储协调器来协调
or more persistent stores and a
一个或多个持久存储
managed object context.
以及一个托管对象语境
And to set that up took a fair
构建一个 Core Data Stack
amount of code.
需要编写大量代码
This is a reduced version of the
这是你为了运行它
code you needed to write to get
而编写的缩减版
that going.
代码
But last year with the hard work
但是去年在 Core Data 团队的
of the Core Data team there's
努力工作下
the NSPersistentContainer class
推出了 NSPersistentContainer 分类设置
setting encapsulates the stack
它囊括了 Core Data Stack
and it's easy now.
现在就变得十分简单了
You just have to do this.
你只要这样操作即可
The key line is to initialize
关键是要使用
your persistent container with
你自己的模型名称来
your model name.
完成持久化容器的初始化
Moving on to number 21, arrays.
接下来是“技巧 21 数组”
I've got my Cat Wrangler
我已经有了一个 Cat Wrangler 应用
application, one of those Cat
它是个猫咪管理的应用
management applications and I
在我的数据模型中
have a cat entity in my data
我已经有了一个
model with a name and a photo
有名字和照片属性的
attribute.
猫的实体账号
And I realize cats also have
但是我发现
behaviors, such as attacking
猫还有各种行为  比如
dust particles, staring at
攻击空气中的尘粒
walls, and playing keyboards.
盯着墙壁看 玩键盘等等
So, I'd like to add an array of
于是我想要加入一个行为数组
behaviors because I think a
因为我认为字符串是一个
string is a good representation
用来表示行为动作的好方法
of a behavior and I just want an
而且我只想要
array of strings.
一个字符串数组
But there's no array type here,
但是这里没有数组类型
well I just transformable
好吧 那我选“可变化的”
because that can be anything.
因为这可以是任何东西
So, I make an array that's not a
所以我创建了一个数组
good idea.
但这并不是一个好主意
There's performance issues,
它出现了性能问题
there's overhead for serializing
它会增加序列化和
and deserializing arrays and
反序列化数组
their contents and also any such
以及其相关内容的开销负担
requests are going to be a lot
而且如果你以这种方式操作
slower if you do things this
任何请求都会变得
way.
更加迟缓
So, we recommend instead making
所以我们建议
a behavior entity and making a
重新建立一个行为实体账号
relationship to the behaviors.
让它与猫咪的行为建立关联
This would be a too many
这样就会有太多关联
relationships because there's
因为有太多的行为动作
many behaviors and I want to
如果我想查看它们是否
check the ordered checkbox if I
遵循一定顺序
care that they're in a certain
我会勾选“排序”
order.
复选框
In addition, this has the
而且 这样做有利于
benefit of allowing me to use a
让我为自己的行为而使用
richer data model for my
更丰富的数据模型
behavior, I can add a duration
比如 我可以添加
for example.
一个持续时间
And so, your data model will
因此 你的数据模型
become more representative of
将更能表示
what you're trying to do.
你想实现的效果
Tip number 34, core data
“技巧 34 Core Data迁移”
Migration is one of the real
迁移是使用 Coore Data 的
strengths of using Core Data.
真正优势之一
I shipped Cat Wrangler and then
我使用了 Cat Wrangler 后
I realized cats also eat food
我发现猫也吃
like grass, cupcakes, meat, and
草 杯形蛋糕 肉
of course broccoli.
当然 还有西兰花这一类的东西
So, I need a new data model, I
所以 我需要一个新的数据模型
copy my Cat Wrangler data model,
我复制了我的 Cat Wrangler 数据模型
make Cat Wrangler 2 and I can
创建了 Cat Wrangler 2
add my food entity to it.
这样我就可以把食物实体账号添加进去
In Xcode, I simply change the
我在 Xcode 里简单地把
current model version to Cat
当前模型版本改成了
Wrangler 2 and then lightweight
Cat Wrangler 2
migration is handled
然后  如果你使用
automatically if you've used
NSPersistentContainer
NSPersistentContainer.
你的轻量版迁移就被自动处理了
If you set up your own stack you
如果你构建了自己的堆栈
have a couple of options that
你需要设置几个选项
you need to set to make the
让迁移能够得以实现
migration happen and that's all
你要做的就只有这些
you have to do.
事情
Tip number 55, error handling.
“技巧 55 错误处理”
In a perfect world we'd handle
在一个完美的世界里
all errors, but everybody knows
我们可以处理所有的错误
it's not a perfect world, the
但大家都知道 这个世界并不完美
world itself isn't entirely
它本身甚至都不是
round.
完全圆的
So, if you can only handle
所以 如果你只能处理
errors in one area in Core Data
Core Data 一个区域内的错误
the most important part is when
那么最重要的部分就是
you've added a persistent store.
添加持久化储存器的空间
If things don't work there
如果它不能成功运行
nothing's going to go right in
那么你应用中的所有功能
your application.
都无法正常使用
If you use persistent container
如果你使用持久化容器
you can see there's the
你可以看见还有
loadPersistentStores method and
loadPersistentStores 方法
some of the things that can
有些事情可能会发生  那就是
happen is you can run out of
你会用尽存储空间
storage space, you can have
你会遇到权限问题
permission issues or data
或数据保护问题
protection or you can have an
要不就是无法打开
older file that can't be opened,
一个旧文件
you don't have a proper
你没有一个合适的
migration strategy for it.
迁移策略来应对它
And if you're wondering how to
如果你想了解如何
present those errors to users
向用户呈现这些错误
Vince has something to tell you.
Vince 会与你分享一些信息
&gt;&gt; All right, tip number 404,
&gt;&gt;  好的 “技巧404
NSError.
NSError”
So, in the rare event that
在小概率情况下
something goes wrong in your
你的应用会出现问题
application you want to give
你可能想给用户
your users great error messages
发出“严重错误”的信息
and Cocoa APIs like Core Data
而诸如 Core Data 这样的 Cocoa API
give you error messages that are
也会向你发出“错误”信息
fully localized and ready to
这些信息已经完全定位并
present to the user and that's
可随时向用户呈现
really easy to do.
要做到这一点很容易
Any responder has a presentError
任何响应器都有一个 presentError 方法
method, you pass in your error
你传入你的错误
and it'll go up the responder
它将进入响应链
chain, if anything NSApplication
如果有错误  NSApplication
will catch it and show a
会找到它  并弹出一个
dialogue.
对话框
And if you have your own
如果你自己有
responder subclass that's
适合显示错误的
well-suited to presenting an
响应器子类
error you can override this and
你可以重写这个方法
present the error yourself.
然后自己来呈现错误
And here's the trick about these
这是关于上述 Cocoa API 错误的一个技巧
Cocoa API errors, you can create
你可能会制造这些错误
them yourself all you need to do
这时你只需要
is create an NSError, pass in
创建一个 NSError
the NS Cocoa error domain, a
传入 NSCocoaErrorDomain
code that matches what went
这个代码可匹配错误
wrong and then a user info that
然后是 userInfo
might have some additional
它可能含有一些额外信息
information like the file URL
比如你正在使用的
you're acting on.
文件 URL
And you'll get a nice localized
接着 你将获得一个很好的  已经定位
user presentable error just like
并且可以向用户呈现的错误 就像这样
that, just like the ones we
就像我们返回的
return.
这些错误
And we have a lot of error
我们有很多错误代码
codes, so hopefully you can find
希望大家能从中找到
something that matches what went
可与出现问题相匹配的
wrong.
代码
This is a snippet of foundation
这是基础片段 errors.h
errors.h, the generated
生成界面
interface, so feel free to look
所以大家能够随意地看
through this, we're not going to
我们不会演示
go through them all.
整个过程
And if the error is close, but
如果错误相近
could be better you can
但还可做到更好 你可以
customize them with the user
用 userInfo 来自定义
info.
这些错误
There are several user info keys
有几个 userInfo 键
that will let you alter pieces
可以让你更改
of the error message.
错误信息
Here we're altering the recovery
我们现在要更改恢复建议
suggestion because we know that
因为我们知道
this error occurred in the
这个错误出现于
context of a download and we can
下载环节 我们可以
tell the user that to help them
把这一信息告知用户
recover.
帮助他们恢复
And by the way, if you're using
顺便说一句
Xcode 9 you can use this new
如果你使用的是 Xcode 9
Cocoa error method to make
这个新的 Cocoa 错误方法可以
creating Cocoa domain errors
让 Cocoa 域错误的创建
even more convenient.
更为便捷
Now if you need an error that
现在 如果你需要一个
Cocoa doesn't provide it's still
Cocoa 并未提供的错误
easy to make your own.
那么你仍可轻松地自行创建
All you need to do is define a
你要做的就是
domain, your error codes, and
定义域  和你的错误代码
then you create an NSError with
然后用那个域  还有其中一个代码
that domain, one of those codes
以及带键的 userInfo
and a user info with keys that
来创建一个 NSError
describe the error message,
userInfo 所带一这个键
provide the error message.
用于描述错误信息  提供错误信息
And you don't need to give those
此外你不需要在 userInfo 里
keys up front in your user info
预先给出这些键
you can call this NSErrorClass
你可以调用这个 NSErrorClass 方法
method, set user info value
设置 userInfo ValueProvider
provider, and you get at your
然后就获得了
domain.
想要的域
And when an NSError with your
然后  当包含这个域的 NSError
domain looks up at a info key
查找 userInfo 键却
and it's not found it will call
无法找到时
this block.
它就会调用这个代码块
And so, you can lazily return
这样 你可以不费力地
values for those keys.
返回那些键的值
And what that means is now it's
这就意味着 现在要
super easy to create your errors
创建你的错误已经超级简单
you just make an NSError with
你只需用你的域和代码
your domain and code and that's
创建一个 NSError
it.
就搞定了
Now there are a lot of
现在 在 NSError 上
properties on NSError, check out
有很多属性 去看一看
the header for more.
页头  获取更多信息吧
I do want to note that a lot of
我确实要提一点  这些属性里有许多是
them have user info keys that
有对应的 userInfo 键
correspond so you can use them
所以你可以在你的
in your user info value provider
userInfo ValueProvider 里使用它们
and return values lazily, so
然后毫不费力地返回值
give those a look.
所以去看看那些属性吧
Now next up is tip number six,
接下来要谈的是
shared keysets.
“技巧 6 Shared Key Sets”
So, if you were creating a lot
如果你在用同样的
of dictionaries with the same
已知键创建大量字典
known keys you can use a shared
那么你可以使用 sharedKeySet
keyset and your dictionaries
你的字典将变得
will be more compact and
更紧凑 性能更好
performant, thanks to proof of
这得益于散列法的
hashing.
证明
So, you create a shared keyset
所以 你用这个 NSDictionary 类函数
using this NSDictionary class
创建一个 sharedKeySet
function and it comes up with
它会生成一个
the perfect hash and then you
完美的散列
can initialize your
然后你可以用
NSMutableDictationaries with
你的 sharedKeySet
your shared keyset.
把你的 NSMutableDictationary
Here's what this might look
初始化
like.
可能像这样
So, you create your shared
你创建你的 sharedKeySet
keyset, it is not trivial to
计算一个 sharedKeySet
compute a shared keyset so it's
不是件简单的事
a good idea to stash it away and
所以把它存放起来
reuse it and create as many
并且重复使用  这是个好主意
mutable dictionaries as you
你可以随心所欲地
want.
创建你的可变字典
And you create your mutable
你创建了可变字典
dictionary and then you can use
然后就 可以使用它
it like any other mutable
就像用其他的可变字典一样
dictionary and even you can put
你甚至可以插入
in keys that aren't in your
不在你的 sharedKeySet 里的键
shared keyset they just won't be
它们只是不会具有
as performant.
同样的高性能而已
So that's shared keyset.
所以 这就是 sharedKeySet
Now back to Rachel.
我现在把舞台交还 Rachel
&gt;&gt; We've come to hexadecimal A
&gt;&gt;  我们现在要讲讲十六进制里代表
for accessibility, get AX
可访问性的 A   听说过
accessibility?
AX 寄存器吗
And Apple has many ways to make
Apple 有很多方法
your products accessible to all
让你的产品可供所有用户
users.
来访问
I'm just going to go over a few
我只介绍其中的几样
small things.
小工具
VoiceOver is not small, but I'll
其实 VoiceOver 并不算小
talk about it briefly.
但我只能简单地谈一下
It comes built-in on all Apple
它内置于所有的 Apple 产品中
products and it's easy to set up
并且可以在界面构建器里
in Interface Builder, I have my
轻松设置
add cat button and I just fill
我有一个“添加猫”的按钮
in the accessibility description
我只要在可访问性描述中
add cat and then VoiceOver knows
填入“添加猫”   然后 VoiceOver
what to say.
就知道该说什么了
Also remember to test your apps
还有  要记得在低分辨率条件下
at low resolutions, low vision
测试你的 App
users want to see things bigger
视力差的用户想把
on the screen.
屏幕内容放大显示
So, for example, here's my Cat
例如 这是我的
Wrangler/screen that I'm really
Cat Wrangler 启动画面
happy with.
我对它很满意
I try it at a lower resolution
我用较低的分辨率打开它时
it goes off the screen, don't
它在屏幕上就模糊不清了
let this happen to you.
别让这种情况发生在你的身上
Last, I'd like to point out the
最后 我想指出
existence of the Accessibility
在 Xcode 菜单中 还可以发现一个
Inspector that's available from
可访问性检测器
the Xcode menu.
的存在
Launch it, run it on your apps
启动它 在你的各个 App 上运行它
and see where you can improve
看看你的 App 在可访问性方面
your apps in terms of being
还有哪些地方
accessible.
可以改进
Back to Vince.
现在把舞台还给 Vince
&gt;&gt; Okay and now toward infinity
&gt;&gt; 好的 现在进入
and documents.
无限性与文件这个话题
So, users today are very
现在的用户非常苛刻
demanding, they expect a lot
他们对基于文档的 App
from document-based apps.
有很多期望
They don't want to worry about
他们不想为保存内容
saving.
而担心
They want it to be easy to name
他们希望能够轻松地
and organize their documents and
命名并组织自己的文件
they want powerful version
他们还想要强大的
control.
版本控制
And they even want features like
他们甚至想要更多功能
iCloud document sharing that's
例如 macOS High Sierra 上新增的
new in macOS High Sierra that
iCloud 文档共享
you will never even have heard
大家可能在本周之前 甚至连听都
about until this week.
没有听说过
What's a developer to do?
开发者要做什么
Well you can use NSDocument and
嗯 你可以使用 NSDocument
NSDocument has a class property
它有一个类属性
autosavesInPlace.
名为 autosavesInPlace
By default, it returns false,
在默认情况下 它会返回 False 值
but you can override it and
但你可以覆写它
return true and you get all of
让它返回 True 值
those features for free, so it's
你将免费获得所有这些功能
pretty great.
所以它很棒
Check out NSDocument if you have
如果你有一个基于文件的应用
a document-based application.
那就查看一下 NSDocument 吧
Next up is number 42, the answer
接下来是“技巧 42 异常报告的
to reporting exceptions.
答复”
For the most part, when
在大多数情况下
NSApplication catches an
当 NSApplication 在捕获异常时
exception it will just log it
只会把异常记入日志
and let your app continue
让你的 App 继续
limping along.
勉强运行
But if you want to add
但如果你想要
information or handle those
添加信息或
exceptions differently you can
用特别的方式处理异常情况
override this NSApplication
你可以覆写这个 NSApplication 方法
method to do your own thing.
从而执行你自己的操作
Now back to Rachel.
现在 请 Rachel 回来介绍
&gt;&gt; All right, to err is human
好的 人非圣贤  孰能无过
and to [inaudible] computer,
在计算机操作过程中
especially when the humans have
在人类已经犯错的时候  尤其如此
erred so we'll talk a little bit
所以 我们来简单聊一聊
about debugging.
调试的问题
You know here's many, many
大家知道   调试工具
debugging tools and I'm just
有很多很多种
going to show you a couple that
而我只向大家展示一些
are somewhat hidden in Xcode.
多少隐藏在 Xcode 里的调试工具
Right above the debug console
就在调试控制台的上方
there's this row of buttons,
有一排按钮
there's the debug view hierarchy
其中有视图层级调试按钮
button, debug memory graph and
内存图调试按钮和
simulate location.
虚拟定位按钮
I'm just going to show you a
我准备只展示
little bit about the view
一些关于视图调试器
debugger.
的信息
Here I have this simple browser
这是一个简单的
sample application and I can
浏览器示例应用程序
expand out the views in order to
我可以展开这些视图
see what's going on, is there a
查看究竟发生了什么
view that's hidden by another
有没有视图被别的视图遮挡
one, which view is doing what.
哪个视图正在做什么事
I can see where the views extend
我可以看到被裁剪视图
off when they're clipped views,
延伸的位置
there's many other things with
自动布局还有很多用处
auto layout that you can use in
大家可以在
this view debugger so check it
这个视图调试器里使用它
out and it'll simplify your
所以大家不妨去看一看
ability to debug your view
它会让对调试视图问题的能力要求
problems.
变得简单
Sometimes the bugs are in our
有时候 错误出现在我们的代码里
code, in which case I've come to
在这种情况下 我要谈到
tip 30512012 right, bug reports.
“技巧 30512012 编写错误报告”
To make it easier for us to fix
为了使我们修复错误的工作
the bugs include steps to
更加容易  需要采取一些
reproduce that's the very most
再现错误的步骤  这是最为重要的
important thing.
一件事
We love it when you put sample
我们非常欢迎大家把示例应用放在
apps in your bug reports,
错误报告中
especially when they build and
尤其是 当这些错误
show the problem on the platform
在你关心的平台上
that you care about.
形成并显示出
Include any resources that are
问题的时候
needed to reproduce your
要把再现问题所需的一切资源
problem.
都考虑在内
And then logs, such as
然后是日志
sysdiagnose.
例如 sysdiagnose
There's a page on
在 developer.apple.com 这个网址上
developer.apple.com that shows
有一个页面  它展示了
how to collect logs for all of
如何收集我们所有平台的日志
our platforms and look through
并通过浏览日志
there see whatever might be
来看看有什么可能会对
helpful to the person who's
正在查看问题的用户
taking a look at the issue and
有所帮助
that'll help it all go faster.
这将有助于整个进程的加快发展
Back to Vince.
下面有请 Vince
&gt;&gt; Okay tip number 44.1, here's
好的 “技巧 44.1”
a really easy way to add bells
有一个非常简单的方法可以
and whistles to your
为你的应用添加
application.
一些花哨的效果
NSButton has a property it's
NSButton 有一个属性
called sound, it takes an
叫作 sound  它用 NSSound 形式呈现
NSSound and it's really easy to
而且十分容易
set.
设置
And if you do when the user
如果你设置了音效
clicks the button it will play
那么当用户点击按钮时
the sound and you can even set
它将播放该音效
it in Interface Builder.
你甚至可以在界面构建器里设置它
So, use this to give your UI
所以 通过它来
that extra pop that your users
给你的用户界面设置出特殊的效果吧
are clamoring for [sound
你们的用户可是嚷嚷半天了
effect].
现在来说“技巧 29”
to give a demo not of an NSSound
我将进行一项演示
playing from a button that would
但演示内容不是按按钮触发 NSSound 来演奏
be a silly thing to demo, we're
那样太傻了
going to show you a macOS app.
我们将展示一个 macOS App
It's a daring entry into the
这是一款大胆进军
overcrowded market of cat
于过于饱和的猫咪管理应用市场里
management applications it's
参与竞争的应用
called Cat Herder and it's
它叫 Cat Herder
completely unrelated to that Cat
它和你们之前听到的
Wrangler app you might have
Cat Wrangler 应用毫无关联
heard about and we're going to
我们将从头开始
build it from the ground up.
创建这个应用
Okay, so we have our project
好 我们已经有了我们的项目
already and here we have our
在这里 我们有
specification for our Cat Herder
针对我们这款 Cat Herder 应用的具体说明
application and it looks like we
看起来
have a list of cats on the
左侧像是有一个猫列表
left-hand side and some add and
以及一些添加和
remove buttons.
删除按钮
And then for the selected cat we
对于被选中的猫
can edit the name and photo.
我们可以编辑它的名字和照片
Okay that seems pretty simple
好的 看起来很简单
and pretty straightforward.
一目了然
Luckily, we have a designer that
幸运地是 我们有一个 Designer
already created a nib for us and
它已经为我们创建了一个 NIB 文件
we can go ahead and look at that
我们继续 来看一看
and it looks pretty good.
它看起来很不错
We can run it.
我们可以运行它
And there we go, but nothing's
好了 但无法连接
really hooked up, nothing's
无法运作
working so nothing does
什么都做不了
So, it's time to write some code
所以 这时候应该写一些代码
to get this all hooked up
把所有这一切整合到
together.
一起来
But what if I told you that
但如果我告诉你
there's a way we can get this
有一种方法可以
user interface working without
在不需要任何代码的情况下
needing any code.
让这个用户界面运作起来  那会怎样？
And macOS has a technology
macOS 有一项技术叫绑定
called bindings that will let us
它完全能够让我们
do exactly that.
做到这一点
So, we can go ahead and go to
所以我们继续
our storyboard and we have our
进入 Storyboard
table view here and a table view
这个是我们的表格视图
is going to show a list of cats,
它将显示一个猫列表
which is probably going to be
可能会有一个数组
backed by an array.
为其提供支持
And it turns out we have a class
事实证明
called array controller in the
我们有一个名叫数组控制器的类
object browser here and we can
位于这边的对象浏览器当中
go ahead and drag that into our
我们继续 把它拖入
scene.
我们的场景
And an array controller lets you
数组控制器可以让你
create bindings to an array of
创建到对象数组的
objects.
绑定
So, we can go to the attributes
所以 我们可以在右上角
inspector here in the upper
查看属性检查器
right and select attributes and
并选择属性
you can have your array
你可以让你的
controller manage an array of
数组控制器处理
whatever class you like or a
你想要的任何分类数组
Core Data entity.
或 Core Data 实体
And we're going to use an
我们将使用
NSMutableDictionary as a default
NSMutableDictionary 作为默认设置
since that just lets us get
因为这只是让我们
things up and running.
开始运行
So, we want our table view to
我们想让我们的表格视图
show our list of cats and we can
显示我们的猫列表
do that by drilling down into
我们可以通过向下展开表格视图
our table view until we get to
来做到这一点
the table column.
直到进入表格纵栏
And we can go over here to the
我们可以来这边
Bindings Inspector, it's in the
找到绑定检查器
upper right it's that little
它就在右上角
swirly boxy looking thing and we
这是一个漩涡纹的盒子式的东西
can click on that.
我们可以点击它
And bind the value of the table
并将表格纵栏的值
column to the array controller's
绑定到数组控制器的
arranged objects.
arrangedObjects 上
And the arranged objects is a
而 arrangedObjects 是
property on the array controller
数组控制器上的一个属性
that is your array of cats
那是你的猫数组
that's meant for the view side
也就是视图这方面所代表的
of things.
东西
So now our table view will
那么现在 我们的表格视图将
create a row for each cat in our
为数组中的每只猫创建一个横格
array and that means it will
这意味着它将
create a table cell view for
为数组中的每只猫
each cat in our array and have
创建一个表格的单元格视图
the object value of that cell
并把该视图单元格的对象值
view set to that particular cat.
设置为特定的猫
So, we can go into our table
那么 我们进入表格视图单元格
cell view and we have an image
我们有一个图像视图
view, a thumbnail and the label
一个缩略图和
for the name.
名字标签
And we can go ahead over back
我们可以继续操作
again to our Bindings Inspector
再回到我们的绑定检查器
and select bind to the table
并选择绑定到
cell view's object value and
表格视图单元格的对象值
that object value again is going
而这个对象值仍将属于
to be one of our cats.
我们这些猫咪中的一员
And we can keyPath into that and
我们可以写入路径
specify the name of the cat and
并指定猫的名字
it will look that up in the
它将在字典里进行查找
dictionary and show it.
并显示出来
Similarly, we combined the photo
与此类似 我们把猫的照片
of the cat to the image view
绑定到图像视图
here just like that.
就像这样
Now that's our table view that's
现在 这是我们的表格视图
it, it's now bound and wired up
就是这样 它现在被绑定并
to the array controller and
连接到数组控制器
it'll show its contents.
它将显示它的内容
Next up we have these buttons
接下来 在这个角上
here in the corner, so array
有这些按钮
controller actually has ID
而数组控制器实际上具有
actions for adding and removing
添加和删除对象的
objects.
ID 操作
And the add method does about
添加的方法会执行
what you'd expect, it creates a
你所期望的操作 它将为
new instance of the object it's
正在处理的对象新建一个实例
managing, in our case an
在我们这个例子中
NSMutableDictionary and adds it
这指的是 NSMutableDictionary
to the array so we can just wire
这个实例将被添加到数组当中
that up.
这样我们可以把它连接起来
And there's also of course, a
当然 还有一个移除动作
remove action that does what we
它将执行我们期望的操作
expect, it takes the selected
它把选中的项目
items and removes them from the
从数组当中进行
array.
移除
And of course, we need to add
当然 我们需要将
some bells and whistles to our
一些花哨的效果添加到
application, that is what we're
应用上 大家都知道我们在这方面
known for.
比较擅长
Just like that and that's the
就像这样
buttons.
按钮就处理完了
All that's left now is the
现在只剩下
detail view on the side.
另一边的细节视图了
So, we can go back to our text
所以 我们可以回到我们的文本框
field -- go to our text field
转到这里的文本框
here that is the name that will
这是名字
allow us to edit the name and we
我们可以在上面编辑名字
go back to the Bindings
回到绑定检查器
Inspector and we can bind to the
我们可以绑定
array controller selection.
数组控制器 Selection
And the selection of an array
数组控制器的 Selection
controller it's a property and
是一种属性
it's a proxy object that
是一个代理对象
represents the currently
它代表当前数组里
selected items in the array.
被选定的项目
So, we can keyPath into that
所以 我们可以在 Selection 里写入键路径
selection to actually allow us
以真正实现编辑操作
to edit and show the name of our
并显示猫的名字
cat and similarly, we can do the
与此类似 我们可以在照片选择上
same thing with the selection
采用相同操作
for the photo and that's it.
就是这样
We've now wired up our
我们现在是在没有代码的情况下
application with no code.
连接了应用
So, let's go ahead and run it.
那么我们来运行一下吧
And we can add our cats, give
可以添加我们的猫
them names, give them pictures,
写上名字 附上图片
add more cats, it's a really
添加更多的猫
amazing application it's so
这确实是一个令人惊奇的应用
handy.
很便利
And since we're using bindings
由于我们使用了绑定
you can update these and they'll
所以你可以对这些进行更新
get updated immediately in the
它们将在表格视图中完成
table view.
即时更新
Just like that we can drag in a
就像这样 我们可以
new picture or a Quick Look and
拖入一张新图片或快速查看
drag in a new picture and it
拖入一张新图片
gets updated in the table view
它同样也会在表格视图中
as well.
更新
And of course, we need to make
当然 我们需要确认
sure our bells and whistles are
我们这些花哨的效果
working [sound effect], great.
能正常运作 真棒
So that's bindings.
这就是绑定
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, you can use bindings to wire
你可以使用绑定
up your user interface to your
将你的用户界面连接到模型上
model without having to write
而无需编写
any of that glue code.
任何粘合代码
Next steps might be using a real
下一步可能是使用一个
cat class instead of a
真正的猫的分类 而不是字典
dictionary or even a Core Data
甚至不是一个 Core Data 实体
entity that way you'll get
那样 你将获得持久的东西
persistent -- your list of cats
你的猫列表将
will persist.
得以保存
But you'll never have to write
但你永远不需要
and for that you will have to
与此而言
write some code, but you won't
你倒是需要写一些代码
have to write that glue code for
但你无须为你的用户界面
your user interfaces and that's
写粘合代码
bindings.
这就是绑定
And back to Rachel.
现在请 Rachel 再来讲讲
&gt;&gt; Okay, so number 29 may have
&gt;&gt; 好的 “技巧 29” 或许
seemed like the end, but we have
看起来像是要接近尾声了
tip and plus one, add your own
其实我们还有 N+1 个技巧
tips.
“添加你自己的技巧”
Some ideas for how to get
一些关于如何获取信息
information and learn more.
并学到更多的想法
We have new revised
我们今年有了
documentation this year, topics
新的修订文稿
are grouped by task.
主题按任务分组
There's a hierarchical structure
有一个层级结构
that allows you to drill down,
允许你向下展开
such as this example of going
例如在这个例子里
down and looking at NSView.
不断打开下一级 查看 NSView
There's three different styles
三种不同的
of presentation, there's
展示风格
reference documents, there's
即参考文档
conceptual articles and sample
还有概念文章和
code.
示例代码
So, there's different ways of
因此 有不同的方法
approaching the material.
来获取材料
We also highly recommend that
我们还强烈建议
people check out the release
大家去查看我们所有平台上的
notes on all of our platforms.
版本发布说明
This is information straight
这是工程师亲自
from the engineer's fingertips
提供的信息
about what's new in every
说明了每个版本的
release.
新功能
Header files are always a good
页头文件始终是一个
source of information with line
很好的信息来源
by line comments about all of
它逐行向我们提供了所有 API 的
our APIs.
注释
On Wednesday in what's new in
在周三举行的“Cocoa 的新功能”会议中
Cocoa we asked people to tweet
我们让人们在 Twitter 上
their own Cocoa development tips
发布自己的 Cocoa 开发技巧
and we collected some of our
我们从中收集了
favorites from Twitter.
我们最喜欢的一些技巧
It was hard to choose, but
虽然很难做出选择
here's some of the tips that we
但这里我们仍然选择了一些
liked.
喜欢的技巧
NSHashTable is like NSSet, but
NSHashTable 就像 NSSet
it can contain arbitrary
但它可以包含任意指针
pointers such as void star.
如 void star
And also, you can weekly
还有 你可以不费力地
reference objects from
从 NSHashTable 中
NSHashTable.
引用对象
Sometimes generics in
有时候 Objective-C 的
Objective-C are a little bit
术语有点复杂
cumbersome looking and you can
你可以使用 typedef 来
use a typedef to simplify the
简化它们并
way they look and clean up your
清理你的代码
code.
还有
In Swift, you can use typealias
在 Swift 里 你可以使用 typealias
to do the same thing.
做同样的事
And if you're coming to the Mac
如果你是从 iOS 进入 Mac 的世界
from iOS you may remember that
你可能会记得
NSWindowController is often a
NSWindowController 是大家
class that you want to use
经常想要用的分类
rather than NSViewController.
而不是 NSViewController
So, check it out and think about
所以去观察一下
it.
思考一下
And our last tip from Twitter is
我们从 Twitter 选的最后一条技巧是
that in Xcode you can use Add
在 Xcode 中 你可以使用 Add Expression
Expression to get Quick Look
来获得任意地址的
previews for arbitrary
快速查看预览
So, here are some screenshots
这是一些屏幕截图
showing how that would work.
它们展示了如何实现快速查看预览
I'm stopped in the debugger and
我的调试器运行结束了
I print out the image, this add
我要打印出
cat image.
这个添加猫的图片
I grab the pointer here and I
我在这里抓取指针
can use the Add Expression menu
我可以使用 Add Expression 菜单项
item and paste in my image
并把我的图像指针
pointer.
粘贴上去
And then if I hit the spacebar
接下来 如果我敲击空格键
I'll get a Quick Look preview of
我将获得我的图片的
my image.
快速查找预览
There's documentation on how to
关于如何让你的分类可以进行快速查找
make your own classes Quick
这方面有相关的文稿
Lookable, so check that out.
不妨去查看一下
And we've come to the end.
那么 我们的介绍就到这里
For more information, you can go
如果你想了解更多信息
to this page, we have several
可以访问这个页面
related sessions that are all in
我们此前已经召开了几个
the past.
相关会议  都在这里面
Check them out on video and, you
在视频上看一看 你懂的
know, cats because we all want
猫嘛  我们都想再看到
to see them.
它们